Preliminary Guide to the Robert Ward Papers, 1950s-2012 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Robert Ward papers 1950s-2012 and undated
Ward, Robert, 1917-
103.3 linear feet
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Composer of operas and other works who won a Pulitzer Prize in 1962. Chancellor of the N.C. School of the Arts and a faculty member at Columbia and Duke Universities. Scores and score sketches, correspondence, scrapbooks, research and information files, writings and speeches by Ward, as well as photographs concert programs, awards, recordings, and other materials documenting Robert Ward's life and work. Music scores and drafts include The Crucible, Ward's Pulitzer Prize-winning opera, as well his symphonies, operas, and other compositions. Also includes a corrected proof of his autobiography.
RL.02000
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, some of the additions to this collection are not immediately accessible, because they require further processing before use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Robert Ward Papers was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1998, 2001, 2003, 2010, 2012 and 2013.
Biographical Note
Robert Ward is a composer of operas and other works who won a Pulitzer Prize in 1962. He was chancellor of the North Carolina School of the Arts from 1967 to 1975, and is now Professor of Music Emeritus at Duke University.
Ward was born in 1917 and began composing as a student. He attended Eastman School of Music and Juilliard School of Music in the 1930s and early 1940s before joining the United States Army during World War II. During the war he served as a band director, and was stationed in the Pacific.
Following the war, Ward taught at Juilliard and Columbia, and continued composing and conducting. His second opera, The Crucible, based on Arthur Miller's play, premiered in 1961 and became his best-known work. He won the Pulitzer Prize in Music for The Crucible in 1962.
Ward eventually left New York and became Chancellor of the North Carolina School of the Arts in 1967; he stepped down to the composition faculty in 1975. He joined Duke University as the Mary Duke Biddle Professor of Music in 1979, retiring as Professor Emeritus in 1987. He continues to compose and live in Durham, North Carolina.
Collection Overview
The 1998 Accessions include scores and score sketches, correspondence, scrapbooks, research and information files, writings and speeches by Ward, as well as photographs and other materials documenting Robert Ward's life and work. Musical works include the operas Abelard and Heloise and The Crucible. (1998-0196, 2500 items, 8.0 linear feet. 1998-0564, 700 items, 22.6 linear feet, ca. 1950s-1980s)
The 2001 Accession primarily consists of scores, program notes, libretti, sketches and other working papers for several of Ward's compositions, especially Roman Fever, Sacred Canticles, Appalachian Ditties and Dances, Sacred Songs for Pantheist, and Songs for Ravenscroft. Also includes several manuscript copies and seven audiocassette tapes of musical compositions by others, including Young Gil Blas by Ernesto Ferreri, Bellarocca by Melissa Malouf and James Legg, and America's Going to the Dickens! by Christopher Coleman. (2001-0105, 148 items, 2.6 linear feet, ca. 1980s-1998 and undated)
The 2003 Accession contains musical scores for Ward's Third Symphony, Concert Music for Orchestra, and Minutes till Midnight. There are also concert programs, newspaper clippings, reviews of Ward's work, and photographs. This is no box list for this accession. (2003-0139, 80 items, 0.9 linear feet, dated 1950-2000 and n.d., bulk 1997-2000)
The 2010-0123 Accession includes musical scores, drafts, proofs, and masters for Ward's 2008 operetta A Friend of Napoleon. Also contains smaller amounts of materials from Ward's other works, including Seventh Symphony; Roman Fever; Dialogues: A Triple Concerto for Violin, Cello, and Piano Soloists with Orchestra; an oboe quintet; In Praise of Science; and Dialogue on the Tides of Time. Other materials include correspondence and clippings from the North Carolina School of the Arts; clippings from the premiere and performances of The Crucible and Ward's Pulitzer Prize; autobiography drafts; and concert programs, clippings, and miscellaneous papers dating from Ward's early career through 2010, with the bulk of the materials dating from the 1990s to 2010. (2010-0123, 2000 items, 3.4 linear feet, dated 1950-2010)
The 2010-0177 Accession consists largely of musical scores, drafts, masters, and other versions of a variety of compositions by Ward. The 1978 opera Claudia Legare is heavily represented. Other pieces include parts of The Crucible, In Praise of Science, Minutes Till Midnight, The Lady from Colorado, Images of God, Lady Kate, Roman Fever, and several other works. Aside from musical scores, the accession includes a corrected proof of Ward's autobiography, SECTV contracts and planning documents, other miscellaneous materials, and 2 open reel audio recordings of quartets playing some of Ward's compositions. (2010-0177, 3000 items, 6.8 lin. ft., dates unknown)
The 2013-0014 Accession consists largely of musical scores, drafts, masters, and other versions of a variety of compositions by Ward. Aside from musical scores, the accession includes awards, photographs, and recordings. (2013-0014, 375,000 items, 50.0 lin. ft., dates unknown)
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Ward, Robert, 1917-; Malouf, Melissa; Legg, James; Duke University -- Faculty; North Carolina School of the Arts -- Faculty; Columbia University -- Faculty; Composers -- United States; Composers -- United States -- Correspondence; Audio cassettes; Scrapbooks; Photographs; Scores
Contents of Collection
- Accession 1998-0196
  The 1998 Accessions include scores and score sketches, correspondence, scrapbooks, research and information files, writings and speeches by Ward, as well as photographs and other materials documenting Robert Ward's life and work. Musical works include the operas Abelard and Heloise and The Crucible. (1998-0196, 2500 items, 8.0 linear feet. 1998-0564, 700 items, 22.6 linear feet, ca. 1950s-1980s)
  - Lady from Colorado, supplementary material (Box 1)
  - Lady from Colorado, former drafts
  - Abelard and Heloise, photographs of Charlotte Opera production
  - Crucible, photographs from Korean production
  - Carmen, miscellaneous materials from Durham production
  - Duke Archives
  - Winterfest
  - 70th celebration
  - 70th birthday letters, etc.
  - Dialogue on the Tides of Time
  - First Performance (various pieces ca. 1991); Recent Publicity and Programs
  - Crucible, 1985-1986
  - Opera, The Crucible
  - Opera, Claudia Legare
  - Chamber Works
  - Opera, He Who Gets Slapped (Pantaloon)
  - Crucible, 1st Performance 1961 Oct.-City Center; March 1962
  - List and bio of composers, 1983-1984
  - Durham Symphony programs and reviews
  - Miscellaneous-news items from Duke students, etc.
  - Opera, Abelard and Heloise
  - Orchestral Works (various)
  - 70th Birthday Celebration
  - Birthday Celebration, address and letters
  - Winterfest, 1985-1986,and Encounters
  - Japan-U.S. Friendship Commission
  - Untitled folders and unfoldered material (bulk of this box)
    Includes various programs, photographs, clippings, and magazines, and journals.
  - Duplicate guest appearances (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous letters, 1976
  - Proofs (photographic)
  - Publicity, reviews (extra copies)
  - 1950 (photographs)
  - Letters, 1977
  - Letters, 1975
  - Oakwood High Band
  - Seoul Opera Group
  - Letters to save
  - Peabody-doctorate
  - Mr. [Eugene] Ormandy (autographed photograph)
  - Untitled folders and unfoldered material (bulk of this box)
    Includes various programs, photographs, clippings, and magazines and journals, scores, awards and certificates
  - Untitled notebook of letters, 1940s (Box 3)
  - Speeches and articles
  - The Crucible in Korea, 1985
  - Abelard and Heloise
  - American Participant Program, USIA
  - Speeches-Articles-Ward
  - Guest appearances
  - Opera, Minutes Till Midnight
  - Concerto for Saxophone and Orchestra
  - Sonic Structure
  - Sacred Songs for Pantheists
  - Organ, Celebration of God in Nature
  - Symphony #4
  - Sketch-libretto and vocal score; revision of Lady from Colorado
  - Michael Charry
  - Minutes Till Midnight, (2 folders)
  - Sets, pictures, Lady from Colorado
  - Crucible, Stambler/Ward
  - Crucible-Pennsylvania Opera Theatre
  - Sketch and copy of original MS, Images of God
  - Untitled folders and unfoldered material
    Includes various programs, photographs, clippings, awards and certificates.
  - Crucible Pictures (Box 4)
  - Lady from Colorado (libretto)
  - Bath County Rhapsody (score and parts, print copy, sketches and MS)
  - Appalachian Ditties and Dances (masters)
  - By the Way of Memories Full Score (original)
  - Serenade for Mallarmé MS, sketches, printing masters, score and parts
  - He Who Gets Slapped, NCSA Production (photograph)
  - Prairie Overture for Concert Band (score)
  - First String Quartet (score)
  - Lady From Colorado (libretto)
  - Sketch, Lady From Colorado
  - Untitled folders and unfoldered material
    Includes various scores, photograph albums, and scrapbooks
  - Sketches-original MS and copies, Second Sonata for Violin and Piano (Box 5)
  - Lady From Colorado (libretto)
  - Various print items, journals and books
  - Oversize Materials: Mainly scores but also a few performance posters and awards (Box 6)
- Accession 1998-0564
  - Symphonies 1-2 (Box 1)
  - Symphonies 3-4 (Box 2)
  - Symphonies 5-6 (Box 3)
  - First Symphonic Set- Four Abstractions (Box 4)
  - Second Symphonic Set- Sorrow of Mydath (Box 5)
  - Abelard and Heloise (Box 6)
  - Abelard and Heloise-Sketches (Box 7)
  - The Crucible-Full Score (Box 8)
  - The Crucible-Scores, Prints, Set Drawings (Box 9)
  - The Crucible-Sketches (Box 10)
  - The Crucible-Clippings and programs (Box 11)
  - Claudia Legare (Box 12)
  - Claudia Legare - Sketches (Box 13)
  - He Who Gets Slapped - Scores, Libretto (Box 14)
  - He Who Gets Slapped-Sketches, etc. (Box 15)
  - Lady Kate-Original Score, Revised Full Score (Box 16)
  - Earth Shall Be Fair (Box 17)
  - Minutes Till Midnight (Box 18)
  - Minutes Till Midnight (Box 19)
  - First Harvest-First String Quartet (Box 20)
  - Images of God (Box 21)
  - That Wondrous Night-Yankee Overture (Box 22)
  - Hush'd be the Camps-Hymn to the Night (Box 23)
  - The Promised Land-The Rolling 7th (Box 24)
  - Sweet Freedom's Song (Box 25)
  - Sacred Songs for P.-Scherzo (Box 26)
  - Dialogue on the Tides of Time-Divertimento for Orchestra (Box 27)
  - Just as You Were-Life of Riley (Box 28)
  - Ode-Processional March (Box 29)
  - Invocation and Tacotta-Jubilation (Box 30)
  - Energetically- Fiesta Processional (Box 31)
  - Adagio and Allegro- Celebrations of God in Nature (Box 32)
  - Movements for String Quartet-Night Music (Box 33)
  - Concerts for Saxophone-Concord Hymn (Box 34)
  - Concert Music-Concerts for Piano (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Scores- Songs for Ravenscroft, Concerto for Violin and Orchestra, Concert Music for Orchestra (Box 36)
  - Early Works-Unpublished Writings (Box 37)
  - Biographical Materials-Miscellaneous Programs, etc. (Box 38)
  - Compact Discs-Miscellaneous (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous- Correspondence, Students Work, Lady from Colorado (Box 40)
- Accession 2001-0105
  The 2001 Accession primarily consists of scores, program notes, libretti, sketches and other working papers for several of Ward's compositions, especially Roman Fever, Sacred Canticles, Appalachian Ditties and Dances, Sacred Songs for Pantheist, and Songs for Ravenscroft. Also includes several manuscript copies and seven audio cassette tapes of musical compositions by others, including Young Gil Blas by Ernesto Ferreri, Bellarocca by Melissa Malouf and James Legg, and America's Going to the Dickens! by Christopher Coleman. (2001-0105, 148 items, 2.6 linear feet, ca. 1980s-1998 and undated)
  - Concert program and newspaper clippings, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Booklet, Opera Carolina, 50th Anniversary
  - Band Score, Concerto for Tenor Saxophone
  - Book, Jacob Avshalomov. Music is where you make it
  - Sketches, Love's Seasons and The Hill
  - Sketches, Trio for Clarinet, Violin, Cello, and Piano, (2 folders)
  - Sketches, Night Under the Big Sky and miscellaneous sketches
  - Piano Score, Concerto for Saxophone and Orchestra
  - Sketches, Echoes of America
  - Program notes, Ravenscroft Cantata
  - Roman Fever, libretto, (2 folders)
  - Piano Score, Concerto for Violin and Orchestra
  - Original MS and Sketch, Sacred Canticles, (3 folders)
  - Working Papers, Roman Fever, libretto, (8 folders)
  - Score and Parts, Appalachian Ditties and Dances, for Violin and Piano
  - Score, First String Quartet
  - Songs of Innocence and of Experience, Ernesto Ferreri
  - Bellarocca, Libretto by Melissa Malouf, Music by James Legg
  - Young Gil Blas, Ernesto Ferreri
  - America's Going to the Dickens!, Christopher Coleman
  - The House of the Seven Gables, Scott Eyerly
  - Correspondence
  - Sacred Canticles
  - Loose Materials, (2 folders)
  - Audio Cassette Tapes
    - Everly: Prologue, House of 7 Gables
    - Fiddlers' Hall of Fame
    - Young Gil, etc.
    - Young Gil Blas
    - America's Going to the Dickens!, Coleman/Stambler
    - Stravinsky-Bloch-Dello Joio-Giannini
    - Soft Sounds and Night Music, Joseph Leniado-Chira, 1993
  - Score, Jonathan and the Gingery Snare; composer's MS, copy, First String Quartet (Box 2)
  - Score, Sacred Songs for Pantheist, (2 folders)
  - Score and parts, Appalachian Ditties and Dances, for Violin and Piano
  - Relations to Rigor, Scott Lindroth
  - Full Score, Songs for Ravenscroft, 1993 (Box 3)
  - [Concert program and newspaper clippings, 1998]
  - Working papers, Roman Fever, libretto
  - Claudia Legare, Libretto by Bernard Stambler, Music by Robert Ward, (2 folders)
  - Unnamed Binder [ Minutes Till Midnight, libretto by Daniel Lang, music by Robert Ward], (2 folders)
- Accession (2003-0139), (2 boxes)
  The 2003 Accession contains musical scores for Ward's Third Symphony, Concert Music for Orchestra, and Minutes till Midnight. There are also concert programs, newspaper clippings, reviews of Ward's work, and photographs. (2003-0139, 80 items, 0.9 linear feet, dated 1950-2000 and n.d., bulk 1997-2000)
  This is no box list for this accession.
  - Accession 2003-0139 (Box 1-2)
- Accession (2010-0123), (5 boxes)
  Accession includes musical scores, drafts, proofs, and masters for Ward's 2008 operetta A Friend of Napoleon. Also contains smaller amounts of materials from Ward's other works, including Seventh Symphony; Roman Fever; Dialogues: A Triple Concerto for Violin, Cello, and Piano Soloists with Orchestra; an oboe quintet; In Praise of Science; and Dialogue on the Tides of Time. Other materials include correspondence and clippings from the North Carolina School of the Arts; clippings from the premiere and performances of The Crucible and Ward's Pulitzer Prize; autobiography drafts; and concert programs, clippings, and miscellaneous papers dating from Ward's early career through 2010, with the bulk of the materials dating from the 1990s to 2010. (2010-0123, 2000 items, 3.4 linear feet, dated 1950-2010)
  - Seventh Symphony (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - A Friend of Napoleon (12 folders) (Box 2)
    Edited and unedited proofs, masters, drafts, printing copies and sketches. Includes manuscript pages, first drafts, libretti, vocal scores, and orchestral scores.
  - A Friend of Napoleon (7 folders) (Box 3)
    Continued from Box 2.
  - Roman Fever (opera)-Vocal score, Xerox printing masters, 1987-1992
  - Dialogues: A Triple Concerto for Violin, Cello, and Piano Soloists with Orchestra
  - Oboe Quintet-original unrevised score and parts
  - Sketch of In Praise of Science-all scores and text
  - Opera arias-ECS Publishing corrections, 2003
  - Sketch for Dialogue on the Tides of Time
  - Clippings re: The Crucible and Ward's Pulitzer Prize, 1960s
  - Clippings re: The NC School of the Arts and other miscellaneous news, 1970s
  - NC School of the Arst-Carolina Theater correspondence, 1970s
  - Autobiography drafts, 2000s (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters photographs
  - Rev. Arthur C. Ludlow sermon, Cleveland, 1908
  - Programs and miscellaneous clippings, early career-1995 (7 envelopes)
  - Programs and miscellaneous clippings, 1995-2010 (7 envelopes) (Box 5)
- Accession (2010-0177), dates unknown, (8 boxes)
  Accession (2010-0177) consists largely of musical scores, drafts, masters, and other versions of a variety of compositions by Ward. The 1978 opera Claudia Legare is heavily represented. Other pieces include parts of The Crucible, In Praise of Science, Minutes Till Midnight, The Lady from Colorado, Images of God, Lady Kate, Roman Fever, and several other works. Aside from musical scores, the accession includes a corrected proof of Ward's autobiography, SECTV contracts and planning documents, other miscellaneous materials, and 2 open reel audio recordings of quartets playing some of Ward's compositions. (2010-0177, 3000 items, 6.8 lin. ft., dates unknown)
  - In Praise of Science, manuscript (Box 1)
  - Sacred Songs for Pantheists, printing masters
  - Song of the Jellicles, piano and narrator
  - "I Ride Along," from The Lady From Colorado
  - Scherzo, manuscripts and piano masters
  - Claudia Legare (5 folders)
    "The South Must Industrialize," as well as the full score's original masters.
  - Minutes Till Midnight, full score (Box 2)
  - Concerto for Piano and Orchestra, manuscript (Box 3)
  - Claudia Legare (20 folders) (Box 4)
    Edited and unedited proofs, printing masters, and drafts, in both original and reduced size formats. Includes full scores, vocal scores, and orchestral scores.
  - Claudia Legare (9 folders) (Box 5)
    Edited and unedited proofs, printing masters, and drafts. Includes full scores, soprano arias, chamber versions, vocal scores, and orchestral scores. Also contains "The New South" orchestral score.
  - Cherish Your Land, full score
  - Bayou Rhapsody, original manuscript and sketch
  - The Hill, voice and piano
  - A Friend of Napoleon, masters (Richard Connell's story)
  - The Lady from Colorado (3 folders) (Box 6)
    Contains masters for various parts, including full score.
  - Minutes Till Midnight (3 folders)
    Scene sketches, vocal scores, and orchestral parts for "Oh Cosmos."
  - Images of God, masters and photocopies (4 folders)
  - Love's Seasons, masters in original key
  - "Come Close, My Beloved, Come Close," duet for He Who Gets Slapped
  - Concerto for Tenor Saxophone and Band
  - Aria for Chamber Orchestra, string masters
  - The Crucible (2 folders) (Box 7)
    Includes string parts as well as music for "John, I Knew You'd Come Back To Me."
  - Roman Fever, full score masters (2 folders)
  - The Scarlet Letter ballet, full score masters
  - Jonathan and the Gingery Snare, full score and brass parts (2 folders)
  - Of the Awfull Battle of the Pekes and the Pollicies, masters
  - Lady Kate (2 folders)
    Includes "I Hail This Land" and a full score of "Western Set."
  - First Sonata for Violin and Piano, score and parts
  - Various pieces (4 folders)
  - 2 open reel audio recordings (Box 8)
    First String Quartet, Arioso for Cello and Piano, Tarantella for Cello and Piano, and First Sonata for Violin and Piano. These materials are restricted until they can be reformatted.
  - Miscellaneous documents, some photocopied, 1918-2006
  - Autobiography, corrected proofs
  - SECTV planning and contract negotiations, 1995-1998
- Accession (2012-0094), undated, (14 boxes)
  Series consists of scores and drafts for Ward's various musical compositions, including operas, concertos, and symphonies. Boxes 3-15 are oversized flat boxes.
  - By the Way of Memories (Box 1)
  - Claudia Legare, (10 folders) (Box 1)
  - Concerto (Box 2)
  - The Crucible, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - A Friend of Napoleon (Box 2)
  - Lady Kate, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - The New South (Box 2)
  - Roman Fever (Box 2)
  - The Scarlet Letter (Box 2)
  - Songs for Ravenscroft (Box 2)
  - Abelard and Heloise, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Andante and Scherzo for Strings (Box 4)
  - Aria (Box 4)
  - The Beginnings (Box 4)
  - Claudia Legare, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Claudia Legare, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Claudia Legare, (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Claudia Legare (Box 7)
  - Concerto for Tenor Saxophone and Orchestra (Box 7)
  - Concerto for Saxophone and Orchestra (Box 7)
  - Concerto for Piano and Orchestra (Box 8)
  - The Crucible, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - The Crucible, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Dialogue on the Tides of Time (Box 9)
  - Dialogues for Violin, Cello, and Orchestra (Box 9)
  - Divertimento (Box 9)
  - Earth Shall Be Fair (Box 10)
  - Fifth Symphony (Box 10)
  - Festive Ode (Box 10)
  - Fourth Abstractions for Bands (Box 10)
  - Fourth Symphony (Box 10)
  - He Who Gets Slapped (Box 11)
  - Hush'd Be the Camps Today (Box 11)
  - Hymn and Celebration (Box 11)
  - Hymn to the Night (Box 11)
  - Hail, Hail, Hail the Bride - The Lady from Colorado (Box 12)
  - Music for a Celebration (Box 12)
  - New Hampshire (Box 13)
  - The Promised Land (Box 13)
  - Pantaloon, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Sweet Freedom's Song (Box 14)
  - Symphony No. 1 (Box 14)
  - Trilogy for Orchestra (Box 14)
  - Untitled (Box 14)
  - A Yankee Overture (Box 14)
  - Adagio and Allegro (Box 15)
  - Lady from Colorado (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook pages (Box 16)
  - Concertos, (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - Scarlett Letter, (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - Claudia Legare (Box 16)
  - Symphonies (Box 16)
- Accession (2013-0014), undated, (44 boxes)
  Series consists of scores and drafts for Ward's various musical compositions, including operas, concertos, and symphonies. Also includes awards, photographs, and recordings. Boxes 19, 22-24 are oversized flat boxes.
  This accession is closed pending processing.
  - Datebooks, bibliography, miscelaneous orchestra works (Box 1)
  - Music (Box 2)
  - Programs and reviews 1997-2006, Contracts (Box 3)
  - Lady from Colorado, correspondence (Box 4)
  - Honors, programs, correspondence (Box 5)
  - Lady from Colorado, other bound scores (Box 6)
  - Choral, Band, Librettos (Box 7)
  - Operas (Box 8)
  - Symphonies/concerti, short orchestral works, orchestral works (Box 9)
  - Band scores, choral music, chamber music (Box 10)
  - Claudia Legare, other music, biography bibliography, thesis about Robert Ward, programs (Box 11)
  - Published music (Box 12)
  - Scores (Box 13)
  - Scores including Claudia Legare (Box 14)
  - Programs, reviews, correspondence (Box 15)
  - Reviews, correspondence, Rochester yearbook 1939 (Box 16)
  - Music, correspondence, miscellaneous, slides (Box 17)
  - Trophies and awards (Box 18)
  - Awards, photographs, score from Lady from Colorado (Box 19)
  - Photographs, trophies, awards (Box 20)
  - Awards and plaques (Box 21)
  - Awards, posters, photographs (Box 22)
  - Photograph scrapbook, awards (Box 23)
  - Awards (Box 24)
  - Awards (Box 25)
  - Awards (Box 26)
  - Recordings, (33 digital audio tapes) (Box 27)
  - Recordings, (20 CDs, 16 DVDs) (Box 28)
  - Recordings, (30 audio cassettes) (Box 29)